dearsystems.com 2018-06-09

# Privacy Policy | DEAR Cloud Inventory Management

The latest revision of this Privacy Policy was published on May 23, 2018.  
Please check back regularly to keep track of any Privacy Policy updates. The previous version of this Policy can be viewed [here](http://dearsystems.com/inventory-software/privacy-policy-pre-gdpr/).  
At DEAR Systems we care about your privacy and believe in transparency. That’s why we are committed to being upfront about our privacy practices. We only collect personal information necessary to deliver our services and we handle it carefully and sensibly.

### A. WHO WE ARE

This Policy explains our privacy practices for dearsystems.com (we’ll refer to it as the “website”, “Website”) and our other services provided by DEAR Systems (“DEAR Systems” together with “we,” “us,” and “our”). We’ll refer to the Website and our other services as the “Services.” This Privacy Policy describes why and how we collect and use the personal information of our customers and website visitors. It also describes your options to choose how we use your personal data and how to contact us with any concerns and requests to in relation to that.

If you have questions about the processing of your personal data, don’t hesitate to contact us through privacy@dearsystems.com .

DEAR Systems, is a software development company established by an international group of financial advisors and software developers. If you reside or are located in the European Economic Area (“EEA”) DEAR Systems is the data controller of the personal data (as defined below) collected via the Website, as set out in this Privacy Policy.

### B. DATA COLLECTION

DEAR Systems processes your personal data so you can better use our services. Below you can find an overview of the personal data that we process, if you give permission for this, and for which services this happens.

#### B.1 Statistics

We use Cookies to collect some of the information set out in this Policy. A cookie is a small piece of data sent from a website and stored in your web browser on your computer, mobile or other handheld device, while you are browsing a website.  
Our Website uses cookies to identify you. Cookies can store your account identifier and website tracking. They can also be used for technical purposes such as keeping track of your current session and enabling you to proceed to the next step and use information which has already been entered (languages and theme choices), so that we can offer improved and more personalised services, products and other relevant communication tailored to you.

You can also modify your Cookie preferences straight from your browser. Please note that if you simply disable all of our cookies or cookies in general in your browser settings, you may find that certain sections or features of our Website will not work, because your browser may prevent us from setting Website functionally required cookies.  
You can find more detailed information about our use of cookies in our [Cookie Statement](http://dearsystems.com/inventory-software/cookie-statement/).  
The data that we collect, exist of

  * data about your activities on our website
  * data about your surfing behavior across various websites
  * your internet browser and device type

This includes: IP address, browser type, operating system, clicks on hyperlinks, the domain name of the website that sent you to our website and all other information that you choose to share when using third-party websites.  
We use these statistics to improve the website and our organizational updates through email and to better tailor our offering to your preferences.

#### B.2 Contact information

We collect the data that you actively provide during the following activities, if you give permission for it:

  * when filling in forms (e.g. sign up, contact, email etc.) on our websites
  * in correspondence
  * during voice calls
  * live chat
  * during a business meeting
  * when creating support ticket through the website

The following data can be collected in our databases:

  * Your name
  * Address
  * Phone number
  * Email address
  * Company name
  * Other personal data that you actively provide, for example by creating a trial account on this website or by phone.

#### B.3 Newsletters

We use MailChimp for sending digital notifications and direct marketing emails when you are trialing our software and managing mailing lists. MailChimp sends these through a server in the United States. They secure your data and are part of a certified EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Your privacy is therefore also respected by them!  
You can find the privacy policy of MailChimp [here](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/?_ga=2.183218479.865591856.1527194883-1023061333.1526409507).

#### B.4 Security measures

We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software to encrypt the information you enter on our Website in order to protect its security during transmission to and from our Website. When storing information, we protect its security by encryption and pseudonymization of critical data.  
To protect against unauthorised access to your account and information, we implement session management and login expiration mechanisms. As an additional safety measure, be sure to sign off when you finish using your account and your computer.  
Although we take all these measures to maintain the safety and security of your personal information, please note that no transmission over the Internet can ever be guaranteed to be secure. Consequently, please note that we cannot fully guarantee the security of any personal information that you transfer over the Internet to us.

#### B.5 Use of your credit card

You may have to provide a credit card to buy subscription from our website. We use third-party billing services and have no control over these services. We use our commercially reasonable efforts to make sure your credit card number is kept strictly confidential by using only third-party billing services that use industry-standard encryption technology to protect your credit card number from unauthorized use. However, you understand and agree that we are in no way responsible for any misuse of your credit card number.

### C. RETENTION PERIOD OF YOUR DATA

Information collected on our website will only be retained for as long as necessary to fulfill the purpose for which it was collected. In general, we will automatically delete your DEAR account information 6 months after you no longer have any active subscription with us. Since we offer a service for customers worldwide and we need to comply with regulations across the globe in regard to retention of personal information related to contractual agreements, provision of services, financial, invoicing operations and tax calculations, a versioned copy of your payment and billing data associated with your past invoices is stored for a period of 5 years after deactivating an account. Your personal data is deleted automatically by our systems in accordance with these retention periods.

### D. PRIVACY RIGHTS

Everyone has rights with regard to personal data. If you would like to invoke one of those rights, you can best turn to privacy@dearsystems.com . We will do our best to process all requests within a month.  
You have the right to:

  * delete your personal data (removal from our databases)
  * access the personal data that we might have on you
  * request to change or delete incorrect data
  * request to stop the processing of your personal data
  * request to limit the processing of your personal data
  * object / resist the processing of your personal data

If you don’t want to receive any newsletters or organizational updates from DEAR Systems anymore, you can unsubscribe at any time through the unsubscribe section in each email of DEAR Systems.

### E. SHARING PERSONAL DATA WITH THIRD PARTIES

DEAR Systems doesn’t share your data to third parties and only provides them if this is absolutely necessary for the execution of our agreement with you or to comply to legal obligations.  
We make a processing agreement with companies that process your data for us to ensure the same level of security and confidentiality of your data. DEAR Systems stays responsible for this processing.

### F. PRIVACY AND SECURITY

#### F.1 We ensure a good security

DEAR Systems truly values your privacy. That’s why we spend time on and give consideration to the security of our systems and personal data. We also want to be transparent about which data we collect and how we do this.  
We won’t only keep the collected personal data secure in our databases. Because the processing takes place in Microsoft Azure Data Centers in USA, They secure your data and are part of a certified EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Your privacy is therefore also respected by them.

### G. UPDATED PRIVACY STATEMENT

#### G.1 Privacy statement update

DEAR Systems has last modified the privacy policy on 23/05/2018 and has the right to change it, if it should be necessary. Within this framework it is recommended to regularly consult the page with our privacy policy. This way, you will have certainly taken note of the modifications.

### H. CONTACT US

#### H.1 Contact

Do you have questions about our privacy statement or the way in which we collect, use or process personal data?  
You can always contact us:

  * Through e-mail: privacy@dearsystems.com
  * On the following address:DEAR Systems  
Office 707, Jumeirah Lake Towers,  
Cluster C, Fortune Tower, Dubai, UAE

#### H.2. Further questions and contacts

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, if you wish to exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal information, or if you want to object to the collection or processing of your data by DEAR Systems, whether entirely or partially, please contact our Data Protection Officer who can be reached at privacy@dearsystems.com.
